### Unsupported Browser

Hello! We’ve noticed that you are using Internet Explorer to access our site. This browser is no longer supported. Please switch to another browser and try again.

[Click here for more information](https://freecycle.helpscoutdocs.com/article/157-cant-access-using-internet-explorer).

All My Towns {{ town.name|truncate(30) }}

Privacy
-------

Last updated 31 January, 2024

**Privacy Policy FAQ**

The following are basic questions you may have about our privacy statement. Where applicable, links are provided to the actual policy statements below this FAQ for further detail.

**Why is Freecycle updating its privacy statement?**

We now meet the high standard required by the European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and have updated our privacy statement to reflect that. We also continue to simplify language and remove jargon, to make our privacy statement easier to understand and read.

**What is the GDPR?**

The GDPR is a regulation intended to strengthen and unify data protection for everyone within the European Union (EU). And because we believe that all our members can benefit from its mandates, we're implementing it globally. The GDPR requires greater openness and transparency from organisations on how they collect, store and use personal data, while also imposing tighter limits on the use of personal data. Learn more [here](https://gdpr.eu/)

**How often do you anticipate updating your privacy statement?**

We will update our privacy statement as necessary to ensure that our policies are in line with international regulations, our services and charitable activities.

**What information does Freecycle collect about me?**

When you visit the Freecycle website or use our mobile app and access information, you remain anonymous but to become a member or make a donation we collect personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide through our website, mobile app or via e-mail correspondence. Learn more [here](#collection) .

**Why does Freecycle need my information?**

An email address and an ID is required of members, primarily so that you may then make and receive posts sharing items via email on Freecycle.org and via our Freecycle.org mobile app. Further information may be gathered should you make a donation to The Freecycle Network in order to process the gift. Learn more [here](#use)

**How is my information used?**

Freecycle uses the data we collect for the following purposes:

* Member / User Support
* Service Improvement
* Future Services Development
* Security, Safety, and Dispute Resolution
* Service Performance Analysis
* Communications, Fundraising and Marketing

**How does collecting my information help Freecycle improve its services?**

We use the information to assure that the Freecycle.org web and mobile app community is functioning smoothly and to make sure that we are offering you the best opportunities to share based on your geographic location. We also collect error reports, so we can make improvements to eliminate potential bugs and combat fraud. And finally, understanding how and when our members collectively make use of Freecycle.org and our mobile app helps us design new ways to make sharing that much better.

**Can I opt out of sharing my information with Freecycle?**

You may view postings on Freecycle.org and our mobile app without sharing any personal information. However, since we don’t request sensitive data such as one’s address, credit card info, etc., we do require a basic level of data (user name, email address) for membership with our charitable nonprofit and for making and replying to posts on Freecycle.org and with our mobile app.

**How do I delete my personal data from Freecycle and what are the consequences?**

You can always alter your personal data or remove you account by editing your account settings [here](https://freecycle.org/home/settings/). If you have further account issues, you may contact our volunteer support team [here](mailto:privacy@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Support). Please note, however, that by deleting your personal data your membership will no longer be functional.

**How long does Freecycle keep my information?**

Freecycle retains personal data for as long as necessary to provide the services and fulfill the interactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes and enforcing our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different services, actual retention periods can vary significantly. For instance, we’ll keep all functional data on file as long as you have an active Freecycle account.

**How is information stored and secured on Freecycle’s servers?**

Freecycle is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. Freecycle.org uses the HTTPS protocol. The 'S' at the end of HTTPS stands for 'Secure'. It means all communications between your browser and the website are encrypted. HTTPS is often used to protect highly confidential online transactions like online banking and online shopping order forms. We also use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities.

**Is Freecycle using cookies to gather information?**

Yes. We may use cookies to verify its visitors' identity to provide services related to the use of Groups. By visiting our website or by using our mobile app, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies for such purposes. You can always adjust your browser or device settings to not accept cookies and similar technologies if this concerns you, but this may limit the functionality of our website for you. More info [here](#cookies).

**Does Freecycle use interest-based advertising?**

Yes. We work with third-party advertisers that utilize cookies and similar technologies to provide more relevant advertising about Freecycle on our website and across the internet. To provide interest-based advertising, the advertisers combine non-personal data learned about your online activities over time to customize the advertising delivered to you. We do not share your personal information to do this.

**What safeguards are in place for children who have access to Freecycle services?**

Children thirteen or older may participate only with the permission and supervision of their parents and/or guardians. If a child has improperly registered on this site by using false information or without consent, we will cancel the child's account and delete the child's personal information from our records. More info [here](#children).

**How can I contact Freecycle if I have questions regarding Freecycle privacy statement?**

If you have any questions about the use of your personal information, please contact us [here](mailto:privacy@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy) or at the  [below address](#contact).

* * *

FREECYCLE PRIVACY POLICY
------------------------

### Our Commitment to Privacy

The Freecycle Network respects everyone's right to privacy. This section summarizes what personally identifiable information we may collect, if any, and how we might use this information. This policy also describes other important topics relating to your privacy. The Freecycle Network reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. We will promptly reflect any such modifications in these Web pages.

### Information Collection

In general, when you visit the Freecycle website or use our mobile application and access information, you remain anonymous aside from capturing your IP address which protects the integrity of the service. We do not require you to register or provide personal information to us in order to view our site or mobile app. There are occasions when we will ask for additional information, such as when you apply to become a member of a Freecycle group or make a donation to Freecycle. In these cases, we will only collect personally identifiable information (such as name, telephone number and e-mail address) that you voluntarily provide through our website, mobile application or via e-mail correspondence.

We will not sell or exchange your personal information at any time. We will collect general information (such as the type of browser you use, the files you request, and the domain name and country from which you request information) to improve our website and mobile app and better meet your needs.

California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA")

Under CCPA, Californian residents have the right to declare their preferences on the sale of data for advertising and marketing purposes. If you wish to change your preferences, click this link to launch our preference portal:

{INSERT data-fuse-privacy-tool DIV HERE}

We use a third party to provide monetization technologies for our site. You can review their privacy and cookie policy at [https://publift.com/privacy-policy/](https://publift.com/privacy-policy/).

Your personal information is retained until you choose to delete your account. At this point your email address and password are removed from our records. For further data removal of any remaining personal info, you may [contact us](mailto:privacy@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy%20data%20deletion).

### Use of Information

An email address and a user name is required of members, primarily so that you may then make and receive posts sharing items via email, the mobile app or directly on Freecycle.org. You may optionally also provide your phone number. Your user name is publically viewable. No other personal information is shared and posting is double-blind until you personally choose to share your email address or street address, phone number, etc. with another member. We do not store any data beyond your email address, user name and, optionally, your phone number. Further personal information would only be gathered should you make a donation to The Freecycle Network in order to process the donation. As a charitable nonprofit, we also send out two fundraising appeals annually via email. It may be necessary, if required by law or if pertinent to judicial or governmental investigations, to release your personally identifiable information. If you have submitted personal information to us electronically and would like it removed or modified, please [contact us](mailto:help@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy%20data%20deletion) . We will use every possible reasonable effort to comply with your request.

### Use of Cookies

The Freecycle Network website and mobile application may use cookies and similar technologies like pixels, tags and web beacons to verify its visitors' identity to provide services related to the use of member tools and options. By visiting our website or by using our mobile application, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies for such purposes. This helps us provide you with the best experience and allows certain parts of our website and our mobile app to function properly. You always can adjust your browser or device settings to not accept cookies and similar technologies if this concerns you, but this may limit the functionality of our website or mobile app for you.

### Children

Children may participate only with the permission and supervision of their parents and/or guardians. Freecycle does not target and is not intended to attract children under the age of thirteen. Freecycle does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under thirteen or send them requests for personal information. Although visitors of all ages may navigate through our website and mobile app, we do not intentionally collect personal information from persons under the age of thirteen. If following a [notification](mailto:privacy@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy%20parental%20notification) by a parent or guardian, or discovery by other means, that a child has improperly registered on this site or via the mobile app by using false information, we will cancel the child's account and delete the child's personal information from our records.

### Links

While Freecycle is highly selective about which sites we provide links to, we do not control these websites, nor do we endorse or otherwise accept responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on third party sites.

### Contact Us

Please contact us at [privacy@freecycle.org](mailto:privacy@freecycle.org?subject=Privacy), or in writing at:

The Freecycle Network, P.O. Box 294, Tucson, Arizona 85702 USA

Follow Freecycle

}

Copyright ©2024 The Freecycle Network. All rights reserved. Freecycle and the Freecycle logo are trademarks of The Freecycle Network in various countries.
